good morning everyone for those of you
in my time zone good afternoon for those
of you in New York all right so today
I'm going to give you a talk about
practical methodology for deploying
machine learning this is a talk that's
sort of an homage to talk by my Master's
adviser Andrew who was a professor at
Stanford at the time he did the original
version of this talk today I'll be
presenting my own take on it and some
updated advice based on the last few
years of advances in machine learning
and in terms of the format of the talk
I'll be able to answer a few questions
live during the talk but for the most
part if there's a lot of questions I'll
need to postpone them until the very end
but if there's just one or two quick
clarification things about the slides
feel free to jump in and as long as
there's a low volume of questions I'll
answer them as we go the basic idea
behind this talk is that I want to help
focus your attention on what drives
success in machine learning I understand
a lot of people at this conference are
just beginning their journey of learning
how to work in AI and how to use machine
learning the thing is a lot of tutorials
and text books and videos about machine
learning don't really focus you on
exactly what will lead to the fastest
improvement in your ability to function
in the field most tutorials that you
read proceed by amassing several
different algorithms inductive
principles inference techniques and so
on they make it seem like the way to
become an expert in machine learning is
to know exactly how every algorithm from
the relevance vector machine to Bayesian
linear regression works so I'd say over
here this is one of the things that
people seem to think drive success in
machine learning it's always nice to
know about more algorithms but I would
argue it's far more important to have
lots of data and to know how to apply
three to four standard techniques when I
say know how to apply I mean to know how
to configure their settings understand
whether they're working well
we're working poorly and understand how
to adjust and react if you find that
they are working poorly so this talk
today focuses on this third topic how to
apply the bread-and-butter techniques of
machine learning as a case study that
I'll use as a running example to help
give you concrete instances of the
different advice that I apply I'll be
telling you about a system that I helped
build at Google this is the Street View
address numbered transcription system
the basic idea is that Google Maps can
give you directions to many different
buildings and addresses around the world
but we don't necessarily have all the
buildings you might want to go to in our
Maps already one way that we can add
more buildings to our maps is to use the
GPS and photo data from the Street View
cars as the Street View cars drive
around different streets they take
photos of everything they see and they
also record the GPS coordinates of their
location when they took the photo so if
we see the address number of a building
and that building isn't already on our
map we could in principle put that
building into Google Maps at the correct
GPS coordinates the problem is there are
an awful lot of address numbers that we
take photos of and it's labor-intensive
to transcribe them and put them on the
map the way we solve this problem was we
built a neural network to transcribe the
numbers out of the photographs and
convert them into a computer readable
digital format so that we could then
update the maps entries throughout this
talk I'll refer to a few different
challenges that we encountered along the
the progress of this project and I'll
describe the way that we overcame each
of these challenges as part of my
general advice for you to apply in your
own work the basic methodology I'm going
to advocate is a three step process in
the first step you identify the needs
that you have for the product or the
service or the research project that
you're building you then use these needs
to figure out what your goals should be
your goals should be specific and
quantitative part of the planning
to choose what metrics you will use to
measure success and exactly what kind of
numbers you need to achieve for those
metrics after you've set up your goals
you need to build an end-to-end system
as soon as possible you don't want to
over engineer your project before you
begin working on it just think of the
simplest thing that can actually produce
a usable output for the task that you
want to solve it doesn't matter if the
output is actually any good or not it
just needs to be something that can
actually be scored using your metrics
once you have the end-to-end system in
place you begin step three data driven
refinement in step three you measure
different properties of your system you
figure out which aspects of it are
working well and which aspects are
working poorly and you use these data
driven metrics to improve the parts that
are working poorly and improve them I
haven't uploaded the slides sorry I can
upload them right after the talk after
you have improved your system with this
data-driven refinement process you might
end up with something that's complex at
the end but it won't be over engineered
it will be engineered to be just as
complex as you need to solve the task if
you design a complicated system before
you've actually started tackling the
problem you might overestimate how
complicated it needs to be and end up
with something that's harder to maintain
and use in your business than you need
all right so that's the overall
three-step process now I'll go through
each of these steps in a little bit more
detail the first step is identifying the
needs of your product or service and
defining metric based goals that will
ensure you meet those needs one thing
you need to think about is how could how
much accuracy you actually need in your
product obviously everyone would always
like to build a machine learning system
that's absolutely perfect but that's
usually going to be extremely expensive
if it's even possible at all so you need
to think about how much time and money
you're going to invest to get different
levels of accuracy and you probably want
to initially plan
for the lowest amount of accuracy that's
actually usable in your application some
applications intrinsically demand lots
and lots of accuracy if you're building
a surgery robot that's going to cut
apart people's veins and stitch them
back together
any machine learning you need in there
needs to be extremely accurate
otherwise you're going to cause lots of
pain and suffering and injury if you're
building a mobile app where you take a
picture of your friends that it says
which celebrity they look like there's
not even really a right answer in that
case so it's alright if you don't
necessarily have the most accurate
machine learning system of all time most
applications fall somewhere in the
middle a lot of a lot of business
applications where you use predictions
to plan investments in sales and
acquisitions and so on they fall into
this realm where if you can make better
predictions than the humans are already
making they'll make money we at least
save money relative to what you do if
you operate it off of the human
predictions and the more accurate your
predictions are the better you'll do but
just getting past the human baseline is
sufficient to have a useful product for
the street view address number
transcription system we determined that
we wanted to have human level accuracy
in our transcription we wanted to make
sure that we weren't getting any address
numbers wrong compared to what human
transcribers would get the reason is
that it's very frustrating if you ask
for directions and then Google Maps
leads you to the wrong address
so we needed to make sure that we didn't
reduce the accuracy below the system
that we were already using in order to
measure the accuracy we were able to
just use the percentage of examples that
are correct that's a relatively
straightforward metric but there's other
tasks where you don't want to just
measure the number of examples that are
correct for example if you're building a
test to determine whether someone has a
rare disease you can just say nobody has
the disease because the disease is rare
you'll get a very high accuracy that way
suppose that only 1/10 of 1% of all
people in the population
have this disease you'd get 99.9%
accuracy for cases like that there are
other metrics that you should use
so precision tells you the number of
detections that are correct in the test
for the disease if you say someone has a
disease precision is the probability
that you're correct that they actually
have the disease another metric is
recall the percentage of positive
examples that you actually detect so in
the disease example this would mean of
all the people who have the disease what
what percentage of them do you correctly
diagnosed as having it for the Street
View application this didn't actually
matter because our different classes
that we were categorizing into you were
the six digit numbers that addresses can
take on there's not any one class that's
extremely rare and another class that's
extremely common one metric we did end
up using that was important though and
that you don't see very often and that I
think should be used more often is
coverage so you probably have a part of
coverage before the idea behind coverage
is you can have a machine learning
system that refuses to classify some
inputs basically if you show it an
example where it's not confident what
the correct answer is it can say I am
NOT confident what the correct answer is
you should not use machine learning to
solve this particular input coverage is
the percentage of examples that the
machine learning system actually
confidently classifies and using this
metric was key to our success on the
street view house number pipeline it's
very difficult to reach human level
accuracy on address number transcription
if you insist
that the network classifies every single
example that you show it but you can
easily reach human level accuracy if
you're willing to reduce coverage if
you're willing to say I'm going to throw
out 6 percent of the examples so that I
can reach 99.5% accuracy on the
remaining ones then you can actually get
as high of accuracy as you want provided
that you're willing to throw out more
and more examples so when we set our
goals for the street view house number
transcription pipeline we set our goals
in terms of accuracy and coverage we
wanted to get human level accuracy at a
specific
level of coverage that we felt was
necessary to justify the investment in
the machine learning pipeline there are
other applications besides
classification out there for example if
you're using regression you need to use
a metric based on the size of the
prediction errors that you make like
mean squared error or mean absolute
error all right so the second stage of
the methodology is where you actually
build your end-to-end system you want to
get your system up and running as soon
as possible so that you can identify
what the real challenges are a lot of
the time the aspects that are
challenging are not the ones that you
thought they would be before you started
building it everything and so you want
to find out what's actually going to be
difficult as soon as possible I'm
advocating building the simplest viable
system first the question is what's the
simplest viable system and and where
should you start what should you use as
your beginning point from which you
start to iterate one thing that you can
do if you're working on an application
that's already been done before by other
people is just to find a published
result in this same field and copy the
state-of-the-art method you might not
want to use literally the method that
gets the absolute best accuracy you
might want to get as simple and easy to
implement one that's very close to the
best accuracy if you don't know of any
existing publications that solve the
same application as you then you
probably need to make a judgment call
about what a relatively standard
algorithm is that you should start with
so now I'm going to give you some
guidance about what some reasonable
baselines are to begin with one of the
first questions to ask today in 2015 is
whether you should use deep learning or
not deep learning is very hot right now
and it's my specialty so you're probably
expecting me to tell you should always
use deep learning all the time
that's actually not the case one of the
first things you should decide is
whether the problem you're tackling
requires deep learning or not many tasks
have lots of noise and very little
structure in them usually if this is the
case you don't want deep learning
something like linear regression will
suffice
if there's relatively little noise in
your problem setup
there's a lot of complex structure then
you can use deep learning so when I say
that something has complex structure I
mean you have a task like looking at an
image or a video or a paragraph and
summarizing what it means to a human
being saying you know this paragraph
contains positive sentiment or negative
sentiment or this photo contains an
airplane those involved really
complicated mappings from individual
pixels or individual characters or
individual words to very high-level
abstract ideas but if your system has a
lot of noise and very little structure
and you're just saying something like
here is a house and I'm telling you how
many square feet it has please tell me
how much it costs then there aren't very
many different variables there the
relationship between them is not very
complicated you can solve that with a
much simpler machine learning system the
best shallow baseline to use in one of
these high noise low structure
situations is to use the system that
you're most familiar with a lot of
people will debate endlessly which
machine learning algorithm is the best
but there are theorems out there that to
actually tell you that there is no best
machine learning algorithm usually
you're going to perform the best if you
use something that you're comfortable
with and that you understand if you
understand logistic regression really
well and you know how to tweak it then
use logistic regression if you tweak
logistic regression effectively you will
do much better than if you use an SVM
and don't tweak it well also the same
the same applies in Reverse if you're
familiar with support vector machines
and you think you understand how to
tweak those then by all means begin to
support vector machines before about
2013 before deep learning became really
effective boosted decision trees were
one of my favorite default algorithms if
you have a good implementation of those
and you feel comfortable using them then
they're a really good baseline in a lot
of cases and I successfully use those
for a lot of robotics problems okay so
suppose that you have a very complicated
problem and you have enough data to fit
it in that case then you want to go
ahead and use deep learning
so what deep learning model should you
use the basic way that you decide what
kind of deep learning model to use is
well first as I said on the earlier
slide if there's already a published
baseline that works well in this task
then just copy the architecture from the
published baseline but if you're working
on a totally new problem and you need to
make your own decision about what to use
the main way you decide is you look at
what kind of structure there is in the
data some data doesn't really have any
structure at all it's just a list of
measurements and you just in this case
you could just apply a fully connected
neural network to it there's no special
structure in the neural network at all
it's just completely specified matrices
at every level a lot of tasks have
spatial structure to them this is things
like images or videos or data based on
on maps or any kind of thing we have
sensors aligned on a grid in that case
you can use a convolutional network a
convolutional network is a kind of
neural network that says it's going to
apply the same little function at every
different point in space and if you
learn that one little function really
well then you can apply it everywhere
you don't need to independently relearn
it at every location in the grid finally
if you have a kind of data that has
sequential structure to it then you want
to use a recurrent neural network this
is if you have something like text where
you want to read a long sentence and
then at the very end you're going to be
asked a question about it
so at the end of the sentence you need
to remember something from very early at
the start of the sentence you might
notice that there's a little bit of
overlap between sequential and spatial
structure you can kind of think of time
and space as interchangeable so there is
a little bit of a judgement call of it
whether you want to use convolutional
orbit current networks in some sense
they are similar things I in recurrent
networks kind of imply that you are
convolving over time but that's that's
maybe a little bit more advanced than I
need to get into right now you could do
reasonably well with the choice of
either a convolutional or a recurrent
Network any time that you have this kind
of structure available okay so
you've decided that you want to use a
fully connected neural network to solve
some kind of unstructured data
processing task what's a good baseline
for that situation as of 2015 I would
say that the best baseline to start with
the one that's really easy to implement
and works well in a wide variety of
settings is the two to three hidden
layer feed-forward neural network these
are also called multi-layer perceptrons
and you can go ahead and add more hidden
layers later if you decide that they're
they're needed but to begin with just
try two three maybe even just one hidden
layer you definitely want to use
rectified linear units as your baseline
don't use sigmoids sigmoids are
considered out-of-date now and rectified
linear units are far easier to use you
also probably want to use dropout
geoffery Hinton's regularization
strategy where you randomly mask out
half of the units on every step of
training to train the neural network you
want to use stochastic gradient descent
and momentum this technique is really
effective it works very well as long as
you have a few thousand examples per
class and it's been applied to
everything from speech to vision to
natural language processing it's it's
really the standard engine that drives
pretty much everything in defining right
now part of the reason I'm doing this
talk and highlighting this as an example
of a great baseline for right now is
that it can be hard to sift through the
literature and determine what the latest
advice is so a lot of people are first
getting into deep learning read that
deep learning is all about deep belief
networks and deep bolts and machines and
so on or auto-encoders
I don't really recommend those methods
right now those were performing very
well from about 2006 to 2012 but they're
complicated and difficult to make work
you need to understand a lot more ideas
to get them to work well and these days
there are very few tasks where they're
actually the state-of-the-art anymore
unless you know for a fact
something like auto-encoders is
necessary to perform well on the
application you're working on you
probably want to default to this
backpropagation based rectified linear
network so that's what you do if your
data doesn't have any particular
structure to it if your data has image
structure then you want to use a
convolutional network so I also have
some pretty strong recommendations for
what to use if you're in the
convolutional setting if you're able to
do it I suggest using an inception
Network trade with batch normalization
you'll read a lot of papers out there
about all these different tricks to
train very deep convolutional networks
and in a lot of cases it turns out that
you can actually train as deep of a
network as you want just by using this
batch normalization algorithm that was
released by my colleagues at Google
earlier this year inception and batch
normalization are somewhat complicated
and not every library offers these kinds
of networks so if you're using a library
that doesn't support for example the
inception Network you can fall back to a
simpler convolutional Network once again
I recommend using rectified linear units
the same as in the feed-forward Network
case so just use a convolutional net
work with rectified linear units regular
as it with dropout and train with
stochastic gradient descent in momentum
alright finally if you have a task with
sequential structure then you can use a
recurrent Network in this case the
standard baseline I recommend is the LST
M developed by step lock writer and your
instrument youever um oh yeah I see
somebody's asking about unsupervised
learning if if your task really is
unsupervised like if your final goal is
not to do classification then go ahead
and use an unsupervised learning
algorithm um it depends which kind of
unsupervised task you want to solve if
you're if you're doing something like
denoising then use a denoising
auto-encoder if you're doing something
like generating new samples then you
might want to use a generative
adversarial network or a variational
auto encoder um let me read the
follow-up
oh yeah hidden Markov models hidden
Markov models are
perfectly fine as long as you don't need
the hidden state variable to be
complicated in high dimensional if
there's a very high dimensional hidden
state than hidden Markov models don't
scale as well as recurrent Nets
okay so popping back to the recurrent
Network situation I would recommend the
LST M as the default model that people
use when tackling a complicated AI
complete sequence modeling task you can
train this in stochastic gradient
descent I've heard a lot of people say
that you don't even need to use momentum
in this case the LST M already makes it
easy enough to optimize that you don't
need that extra step but momentum is
usually helpful one thing that's really
important when training any kind of
recurrent network is to apply gradient
clipping that means that during back
propagation as the gradient flows
backward through the network you impose
some maximum size on the gradient and if
the true gradient exceeds that sides you
just you clip it to be smaller than then
what the math actually says it should be
the reason for this is that when you
propagate backward through several
hundred steps in an LST M it can make
the gradient become quite large and a
very large gradient can actually do a
lot of damage if you take a gigantic
gradient step so just by just by
clipping it you can avoid that
instability problem so I see there's a
question about whether google has any
new methods to parallelize llst m as
well I don't actually know anything
about the pyramid lsdm myself so one
thing is at Google we do train a lot of
things using asynchronous gradient
descent where we just train many copies
of the LST m simultaneously that's using
our internal disbelief library um that's
not really something that people outside
can just grab and use but there are
other multi replicas learning strategies
that have been made public one last
trick that you should probably use in
your baseline for a recurrent Network is
setting the forget but get the forget
gate bias to be high that makes it so
that the forget good of the LS TM
initially says not to forget anything
and that helps to make sure
that information flows through the
network originally all right so stage 3
of this methodology pipeline is to do a
data driven adaptation after you've got
your baseline in pit in place you choose
what to do next based on data I'm an
important thing in this step is to not
believe hype about different kinds of
algorithms out there every week there
are dozens of papers appearing in
archives saying you know we have this
new like lingerie in Bayesian
variational variant of this algorithm
you're already using and if you use this
it's going to be a million times better
most of the time most of these papers
are just one author trying to get
attention for their own method and try
to build their resume it takes quite a
long time for an algorithm to get
established and for you to really know
that it's trustworthy so filter out a
bit of the noise try to take a bit of a
conservative approach to what algorithm
to use and expect most of the benefit
you get from doing very bread-and-butter
stuff where you adapt the settings for
the algorithm you're already using or
you gather more data and when you do
change from one algorithm to another it
shouldn't be just because you've read
that some tool is the hottest new thing
it should be because you've used a
metric to figure out what the best next
step should be the most important
metrics are the training error and the
tester you measure how well you're doing
on the training set and you measure how
well you're doing on the test set if
you're not doing well enough on the
train set then you're under fitting and
if you're not doing well on the test set
then you're overfitting so I'll talk a
little bit about how to address each of
these problems if you have high training
error there's a few different steps you
should take I'm most most textbook
advice will immediately start telling
you how to do things to your machine
learning model but I actually say the
very first thing you should do is check
whether your data has a problem make
sure that hasn't been collected poorly
or something like that
if the data has defects then your
algorithm won't be able to fit it next
you should actually inspect your
software for defects and specifically
I'd say don't make your own software
unless you definitely know
you're doing using other established
software that's been tested and improved
by many people is a good way of being
relatively confident that your high
training or doesn't come from a bug once
you're sure that both the data and the
algorithm are correctly gathered and
correctly implemented you can begin to
address high training error by adapting
the learning rate and adapting the other
settings that affect the optimization
procedure you can also make your model
bigger so that it can fit a larger
training set I'll give you a few
examples of each of these things here so
for the Street View transcriber one of
the biggest things we did was we changed
the way that we cropped the photos that
were provided to the system after we had
built our baseline we started looking at
which examples it was getting run over
here on the left here's an example of a
kind of mistake that it was making we
would see these photos that say six six
two four and the correct answer is two
six six two four so we realized that our
automatic cropping system was actually
cropping a little bit too tight we
solved that just by telling it to make
whiter crops and now you can actually
see the complete digit the complete
address number so this is a really
simple and dumb mistake and it's very
simple to fix it doesn't require any
real knowledge of machine learning to
fix all we did was look at what mistakes
were happening and then try to
categorize them and figure out what the
largest bottleneck was so that was our
biggest change that we did in terms of
how much it improved our performance was
we found that sometimes the crop was too
tight and we were misclassifying
examples because of the crop our biggest
change during the development of the
pipeline was not to change algorithms
introduced unsupervised learning
anything like that it was just to
measure where the mistakes were
happening and make a very simple
common-sense change you can also fit the
training set better by increasing the
size of the model here we have a graph
of how our important our performance
improved as we added more layers to this
tree tree transcription system this is
pretty simple we just kept adding more
hidden layers and the performance kept
going up a lot of the time if you have a
lot of data you'll find that you can
keep making the model bigger and bigger
and you always see an improved
a lot of the time you'll end up finding
that your performance is limited by the
size of the model that you're able to
afford to run okay so that's what you do
if you have high training center what if
you have high test set error one thing
you can do is you can dupe data set
augmentation where you make multiple
copies of your training examples
transformed in different ways that's a
relatively cheap way of getting more
data you can also just pay to get more
data if you aren't using a
regularization strategy like drop out
already then you can add drop out and
hope that it that reduces your test set
error so here's a graph of what happens
as you increase your training set size
on the right I'm plotting the optimal
size of the model so as you get more and
more training examples you'll need to
you'll need to use larger and larger
models on the left I'm showing a few
different things that happen one of
these is the training set error the
optimal model size most of the time in
deep learning your optimal model is
going to get zero training error and the
question is just how badly does Nover
fit what is the gap between train and
test performance you'll see that test
performance drops over time as the
training number of training examples
increases so a lot of the time the size
of your data set is the most important
factor driving your success so that's
the end of my talk if you'd like more
information feel free to look at the
deep learning textbook that I'm writing
along with Joshua Ben geo and Aaron
kohrville it's online at Goodfellow
github that I owe and the subdirectory
is DL book so I'm still here for another
20 minutes for questions I'll go ahead
and turn on the camera all right so I
see somebody asks is there any
interactive tool to choose the best AI
algorithm the there is no one best AI
algorithm there's a theorem called the
universal or sorry the no free lunch
theorem it says that if you average over
all possible problems all machine
learning algorithms perform equally well
according to one performance metric so
that means usual
what you need to do is find the best
machine learning algorithm for the task
that you are trying to solve rather than
find the one single best machine
learning algorithm
I see somebody has suggested the Auto ml
challenge I'm not familiar with that one
in particular there are a lot of
contests out there there are a lot of
contests hosted on Kaggle comm for
example so you can look and see if
Kaggle comm has hosted a contest on a
subject that's related to the one you're
trying to solve and if they have it you
can also pay them to host your own
contest if you gather a training set and
so on alright I see somebody has asked
in most supervised problems there is a
predefined number of classes to choose
from and it is often hard to define and
learn an appropriate set of training
data that does not belong to those
classes eg the non-faces for face
detection or the unknown subjects and a
face recognition system are there better
ways to deal with this problem rather
than just training with huge sets of non
class data so in in that case I guess
you're saying you want to learn to
reject things that are not positive
examples one thing you can do is you can
just synthetically generate non class
data another thing you can do is you can
use Bayesian methods that automatically
reduce the probability of specific
classes if they're far from anything
you'd seen in the training set so like
if you use some kind of Gaussian process
regression it's not really going to have
low confidence if the input doesn't
resemble something it was in the
training set provided that you have some
kind of RBF kernel I see somebody asks
is there a limit for the size of data
set at different deep learning
algorithms can handle I know there
really isn't one of the great things
about deep learning is that it's
trainable using stochastic gradient
descent so you just load mini batches of
examples and the cost of each step of
training doesn't really change based on
the size of the whole training set it
only changes based on the size of the
mini batch that you use so you can train
with a trillion examples and use a mini
batch of size 100 and you'll do
perfectly fine that's one of the main
advantages of deep learning over kernel
machines
if you use something like a colonel eyes
svm you usually need to build a gram
matrix where it's size is the number of
rows is equal to the training set size
and the number of columns is also equal
to the training set size so you get
quadratic scaling in memory and time
with training set size deep loading
completely avoids that problem somebody
asks our neural networks still better
for unstructured data I would say it
depends on what exactly you mean by
unstructured if you mean unstructured in
the sense that nobody has curated it and
divided it into different topics and
fields that have been specifically
labeled then I'd say neural networks are
probably a pretty good bet do I know of
any library that can be used in android
I don't off the top of my head at least
not anything that's that's released
publicly but I know different companies
have things internally have you seen the
tool K Xen that's just the model based
on the data you have I have not seen
that tool it is conceivable that you
could build a classifier that tells you
which tool to use though somebody asks
what is an average day at Google like
for me ok so everybody at Google has a
very different schedule really so
anybody you ask is going to tell you
something very different um I don't
manage anybody so I don't actually spend
any of my time on managing people if you
asked for example my manager or his
manager what their day is like they'd
spent a lot of time meeting with their
reports I don't do that unless I have an
intern um a lot of the time I go to
several different meetings for different
projects and I help people figure out
what machine learning algorithm they
should be using or if I figure out if
they need me to invent some kind of new
technique for them to use for their
project I spend an hour - every day
working on the deep learning textbook
and I spent a few hours coding and
working on my own personal research
projects and I spent a lot of time
looking at the output of experiments
that I launched a few days earlier um
this question about advice for deploying
ml as a service
I don't have any broad general advice if
you want to ask a question that's like
if it is a specific aspect of ml as a
service that you're wintering about you
can ask that down below and I'll answer
it when I when I scroll down to there
somebody asks are cnn's limited in the
number of classes so you're always
limited in terms of the memory cost of
storing the weight matrix of the output
layer and if you have an extremely high
number of classes it can get expensive
to store that weight matrix there are a
lot of techniques that people use to try
to reduce that cost like using a
hierarchical softmax
rather than using one big softmax with
one big weight matrix another thing you
can do is you can factor your weight
matrix to have a bottleneck in it the
other thing that limits how well a
convolutional network can do in terms of
number of classes is just making sure
that you have training data for all
those classes you probably want to have
a few thousand examples for any class
that you care about recognizing really
accurately but the the requirement that
you have training data for all the
classes applies to pretty much every
machine learning algorithm right now
someone asks is there an LS TMR in an
algorithm for regression not
classification prediction of numerical
sequences and yeah there is one thing
that's really cool about neural networks
is it usually doesn't really matter
whether you're doing classification or
regression you just need to write down a
loss function that makes their output do
what you want it to do so anytime you
have a neural network and you want it to
output some number that you want to use
as a probability then you use that
number as the appropriate parameter of
some probability distribution so if
you're doing classification you say I'm
going to take the softmax of the output
number and that's going to give me a
distribution of your classes if you're
doing regression you say I'm going to
take the output number and I'm going to
use the output as the mean of the
Gaussian distribution and then I'm just
going to take that Gaussian distribution
measure the log likelihood of the
training data under that distribution
and I'm going to have gradient descent
minimize the negative log likelihood
someone else asks if I've played with
wet labs AI that can apparently find the
best parameters like learning rate etc
yeah so I have used wet lab on a few
different occasions back before wet lab
was called wet lab it was an open-source
product called spearmint I've written a
few different papers over the years if
anybody's followed those papers closely
the first time I tried using spearmint
was for the multi prediction deep
Boltzmann machine paper and it didn't
really work and then the next time I
tried it was for the max out networks
paper and it also didn't really work
there but let me explain a little bit
about why I think it didn't work for me
both of those papers had a lot of
different kinds of parameters that I was
trying to fit around maybe 40 different
parameters and a lot of them were for
things like the sizes of different
layers or the sizes of convolutional
network kernels or the number of layers
in the network for things like that
where you're determining the actual
architecture of the network I think that
what lab doesn't work as well I think it
probably works okay for the learning
rate and so on more recently I tried
using wet lab the actual wet lab product
for the paper that I published it I
cleared this year explained us
explaining and harnessing adversarial
examples in that case I was just using
it to choose the learning rate and
momentum parameter and in that case it
actually still didn't work very well for
me and I don't have a very good
explanation of why some of my other
friends and colleagues I do have
positive experiences with wet lab for
example George Dahl who sits right
across the table from me at Google has
used wet lab and says that it it usually
produces outputs that perform about as
well as the values he chooses himself
but he can find them with less effort if
he uses wet lab somebody asks if I think
that generative adversarial Nets have a
brighter future that variational
inference I think it's really hard to
call I think the idea of research is
people should explore many different
ideas in parallel to each other they're
also not necessarily
mutually exclusive like you could
imagine using variational inference to
recover the code in a generative
adversarial Network or you can imagine
using a generative adversarial network
to define your variational distribution
so I think every serial training and
variational techniques are both
important tools for future research
directions
okay so I've worked my way through the
question queue if any other questions
pop up I can answer them I'll hang out
for another minute or so and if there's
no new questions in I'll let you move on
thanks to everyone who's saying they
enjoyed the talk all right so it looks
like that's the end of the questions
I'll post the slides on on Google+ in
just a minute and you can just search
Google Plus for E and Goodfellow and
you'll see the link of the slides there
um and yeah have a good day everyone
you